Email:tkumar.sap.abap1987@gmail.com

Phone: +91-9886954073

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

	Over 8 years of professional Experience in programming as ABAP/4 Technical Consultant.
	Maintained Structures and Tables in Data dictionary. Created new Data elements, Fields and
	Transparent tables, Generate Table Maintenance, Created collective/ elementary search helps.
	Experience in EWM Related objects in 2+ years.
	Good functional knowledge of SD, MM, FICO, EWM, CRM Technical, ATTP, GTTS.
	Extensive knowledge of RICEF objects.
	Experience in creation and changing of Classical, Interactive and ALV reports.
	Expertise in Data Migrations/Conversions using BDC Programming on Call transaction and Session
	method and also migrated data using LSMW.
	Worked on interfacing using standard and custom BAPIs for distributed systems in SAP R/3 .
	Developed and modified Forms using Smart forms and Adobe forms & SAP Scripts.
	Expertise in Performance tunning .
	Experience in developing reports in OOPS ABAP.
	Enhanced the SAP standard functionalities using User Exits, BADI's and Enhancement Frameworks.
	Good Understanding of both Business processes and technical development.
	Strong analytical and problem solving skills with excellent interpersonal and communication skills.
	Positive work attitude and self motivated to work independently and as well as in a team.
	Worked on New Inline EHP 7.4 Syntax
	Created on AMDP & CDS View and Knowledge on CDS views.
	Worked on Odata Created Deep Entity and Basic Odata related Objects.
	Worked on IDOC for Standard IDOC to send Material to EWM.
CAD/A	DAD CLUL
SAP/ A	ABAP Skills:
	ABAP/4 Tools: Data Dictionary, Transport organizer, Transactions.
	ERP: ECC 6.0
	Reports: Classical, Interactive and ALV Reports.
	Interfaces: BAPI, RFC
	Conversions: BDC Batch Input, session, Call transaction and LSMW.
	Enhancements: Researching, Recommending and developing User exits, BADIs, enhancement points.

☐ **Module Pools:** Screen Painter and Menu Painter using Dialog Programming.

Education:

☐ **Forms:** Smart Forms.

Debugging.

➤ I had Completed my MBA from Osmania university in 2011.

Experience:

- ➤ Working in GeniusBusiness Solutions, Hyderabad as SAP ABAP Senior Consultant from Feb 2023 to June 2023.
- ➤ Worked in ATG, Hyderabad an SAP ABAP Consultant from April 2020 to Jan 2023.
- ➤ Worked in ADS Solutions, Hyderabad as an ABAP/4 Technical Consultant June 2016 to March 2020.

Work Experience:

Company Details:GBSI

Project : Exact Sciences / Implementation **Position:** ABAP/4 Technical Developer.

Modules:SD,MM,EWM,FI

Environment: SAP S4 Hana (Implementation and Support)

Feb2023 – June 2023

- ➤ Worked on Sales Register & Backlog Report
- ➤ Worked on Invoice form for Printing
- Worked on Consignment Report for SD
- > Developing reports for order status report using ALV Grids.
- > Created an interactive report in SD using ALV which gives details of sales representatives, Customers, Net Amount, Commissions, Commission Amount.
- > Created an Open Sales Order Report which displays Material, Customer Number, Customer PO, Ordered quantity, Invoiced Quantity, Remaining Qty.
- ➤ Worked on EWM Material Report and product Master Report
- ➤ Worked on Variance Price Report
- ➤ Worked on Packing Label report for Reprint
- > Worked on IDOC and Ontime shipment report
- ➤ Implemeted Badi for BADI_ACCOUNTDOCUMENT
- > Implemented Online shipment report for SD
- ➤ Implemented BTE to added new fields in FBL1N,FBL5N,FBL3N
- > Implemented FI report for GL Ageing report

Company Details: ATG Project :BCD Travels

Position: ABAP/4 Technical Developer.

Modules:SD,MM,FICO,FICA

Environment: SAP ECC6 (Support Project / Implementation)

Sept 2021 – Sept 2022.

Responsibilities:

Worked as Technical Consultant responsible for preparing technical design document based on the **RICEF** elements. Closely worked with Functional Consultants to understand the business process on the above Mentioned modules to modify the objects based on the client requirements.

- ➤ Worked on Business Partner App using Odata.
- ➤ Created Upload Program from AL11 to SAP To process the Files.
- > Created Function module for CIT Creation & BIT Creation programs.
- > Developed Sales Operation Report to list customers and associated sales Partners as on date.
- > Developed Supplier Vendor Application and PNR App using Odata.
- ➤ Developed Smart Form for Invoice & Form Changes related to Adobe forms.
- ➤ Developed BADI implementation for validate the PO Creation time.
- ➤ Implemented BADI For Account Document post for update the Ref1,ref2 fields in FB03.
- ➤ Worked on Automation process for Gabro application Process.
- ➤ Worked on PO Variation report for based on Parent and Contract PO.
- ➤ Worked on Sales Contract Price Automation for SD module.
- ➤ Worked on CRM Technical side for Automative Project.
- ➤ Implemented forms for Payment advice form
- ➤ Implemented form for Invoice, Credit note, Tax Invoice
- ➤ Worked on Taxpayment Report

Company Details: Aeries Technology

Project : Flexsteel Industries

Position: ABAP/4 EWM Technical 1 Developer.

Modules:SD,MM,FI,EWM

Environment: SAP ECC6 and EWM (Support Project/Implementation)

April2020- August 2021

- ➤ Created custom Smart form ZSD_INVOICE_MAIN for invoice printing. The invoice is customized to print different Logos / Remit address / Payment address as per company code and profit center.
- ➤ Developed Quality Check Option in RF Screen in PGI level.
- ➤ Developed PPF Action definition in SPPFCADM T-code to Print Pick Labels.
- > Added few custom fields in WH monitor report.
- ➤ Worked on VOFM routines for Pricing Procedure
- ➤ Worked on User exits to save the Sales order for T-code VA01 & VA02
- ➤ Worked on EWM GR program for Desktop transaction for Inbound Process.

- ➤ Developed Labels for Bin to Bin transfer for Putway.
- ➤ Worked on Labels for Pick Label, Picklist, Packslip forms
- ➤ Create Custom RF Screen according to Customer Requirements.
- > Worked on CIF for shiffing the Material and Batch Transfer
- ➤ Monitoring the SM1,SMQ2,SMQR T-codes
- ➤ Added custom node for Monitor Transaction and Added additional fields in the Monitor Reports

Company Details:Global Nest Project: Meghathern Electrical

Position: ABAP/4 Technical Developer.

Modules:SD,MM,FICO

Environment: SAP ECC6 (Support Project) Nov 2019 to March 2020

Responsibilities:

Worked as Technical Consultant responsible for preparing technical design document based on the **RICEF** elements. Closely worked with Functional Consultants to understand the business process on the above mentioned modules to modify the objects based on the client requirements.

- Extensively worked on **LSMW** (recording method) to load **material master data**.
- ➤ Developed a report to display list of material document, document segment, Accounting for vendors, purchasing group according to plant, posting date and material type.
- ➤ Developed BDC Programs for uploading Customer data, Sales order data etc to SAP by using Batch Input and Call Transaction Methods.
- > Developed Sales Operation Report to list customers and associated sales Partners as on date.
- > Created a program with the BAPI_PO_CREATE to create purchase order .
- ➤ Developed Smart Form for Purchase order sheet.
- ➤ Interacted with customer support regularly, in order to generate the reports required and to resolve the existing issues.
- > Developed report that generates customer summary balances for the selected date.
- ➤ Developed an Interactive report, to display the Vendor balances in the given fiscal year and then to display the individual vendor balances for each month.
- ➤ Supported several Reports and layouts for handling unexpected errors.
- > Developed an ALV Report to maintain minimum stock of material in an organization.

Project : Philip Morris / Support with Implementation

Position: ABAP/4 Technical Developer.

Modules: SD,MM,FICO ,QM **Environment:** SAP ECC6

Responsibilities:

As a Team Member involved In Business Analysis and Gathering Requirements and also involved in ABAP/4 Programming, **Performance Tuning**, Customization and Implementation of the programs developed.

- > Developed stock status (along with value) report by storage location wise.
- ➤ Developed Technical spec's.
- ➤ Modified the Sales Order User Exit MV45AFZZ for entering the data in customer table.
- > Developed **LSMW** programs to load purchase orders data using Batch/Direct Input method.
- ➤ Worked with **BAPI_PO_CHANGE** for changing the PO with updated G/L Account derived by the logic based Material & Vendor.
- ➤ Worked on BADI Implementations for SD module, **BADI_SD_SALES**, **BADI_SD_SALES_ITEM**. The method **ITEM_CHECK** checks whether the line item has a hazardous material and displays a pop up message if there is a hazardous material.
- ➤ Developed SAP enhancement for VL01 (create delivery order) through user exit for adding additional check for storage location equal to space and delivery quantity less than one.
- > Developed **Smart forms** and associated driver programs for sales order data and converted them to PDF format.
- > Uploaded the details of the Vendor like Name, Address etc through FK01 Transaction.
- > Uploaded the changes done like changing the Tax codes of the vendor through FK02 Transaction.
- > Implemented the **BADI** for the transactions **VL02 & MM02**.
- ➤ Worked on conversion for Customer Master Data (KNA1) using **BDC**.
- ➤ Implemented **BADI** for document items in sales order for checking whether the line item has a hazardous material and displays a pop up message if there is a hazardous material.
- ➤ Using **Module pool program** designed a screen with an input field for customer number and three check boxes for Name, City and Address. Upon entering the customer number and selecting any of the check boxes, the corresponding data should be displayed.

Company Details:Invenio business solutions Pvt Ltd **Project :** MCR Safety Support with implementation

Position: ABAP/4 Technical Developer.

Modules:SD,MM,FICO Environment: SAP ECC6

Responsibilities:

Worked as Technical Consultant responsible for customizing the **RICEF** elements. Closely worked with Functional Consultants to understand the business process on the above mentioned modules to modify the objects based on the client requirements.

- > Designed and developed Goods issue **ALV List Display Report.**
- ➤ Developed a report to Display Purchase order quantity and goods receipt for a given vendor list or purchase organization.
- > Created Stock Transfer Report in ALV which displays the Amount of stock transferred from one Plant to another plant and also the stock remaining after dispatch to other location.
- ➤ Converted Standard Reports to ALV Reports using Function Modules.
- ➤ Developed **LSMW** program for uploading Customer Master & purchasing info records into sap system using Batch Input recording method.
- > Enhanced Customer Master Transaction using **CUSTOMER_ADD_DATA BADI**.
- ➤ Created **Module pool program** for table ZMM_Material based on table MARA on customer requirement. It was showing all the details of particular material based on material document number and year in another screen if the material is not there it was showing the error message in another screen.
- ➤ Developed BDC Programs for uploading material master data, Sales order data etc to SAP by using Batch Input and Call Transaction methods.
- ➤ Worked on BAPI by calling Function Module RV_DELIVERY_CREATE to create Delivery.
- ➤ Worked on Proxy Interface.
- ➤ Create Smart forms According to Client Requirements.

Project: Support (Glochem Industries)

Position: ABAP Developer

Modules:SD.MM

Environment: SAP ECC

- ➤ Working as Support Tickets to change the Small fixes in existing programs
- ➤ Worked of Smart forms issues
- ➤ Worked on New reports for SD,MM
- Worked on Badi to update the reference field in FB03
- ➤ Worked on IDOC report to show the message related segments with status
- Worked on PO Badi to validate the data at the time of PO Creation
- > Created on OOPS ALV report to show the report in multiple tabs.